人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
翻译   辰星晓Reginamoon   -小y   吃冰棒   哈里不是波特
翻译    米糊   冬野   哨厨   易碎的绝对
翻译    DerbyNinja   Caroline   冰岛豆腐
校对    苏葵
时间轴    Caroline   爱说谎的孩子
事实
后期    MythCreator
1991年  有一份文件
被锁在了中情局局长的保险柜里
总监    苏葵
其上晦涩难懂的信息中提到了一个古老的入口和一个未知的地点
文件中还包含着这样一句话
它就被埋在世上某处
求求  求求你了  不要
Please. Please, don't.
如果它能带给你宁静
你今天就给大家上了宝贵的一课
有时人会忘了自己是人  以为自己是只鸟
所以我们必须剪掉他的翅膀
土耳其  阿勒省
三年前
提到过去的符号
When it comes to symbols of the past,
如果它们曾经有重大意义
what was relevant then
那么如今也依然有
is relevant now.
确实  如今少有人相信
Sure, there are a lot less people
如尼文可以用来操控天气
who think they can change the weather with runes
或是五芒星可以用来召唤恶魔
or summon the devil with a pentagram.
我正看着你呢  克拉克
Looking at you, Clark.
但依旧有不少人
But there are still a lot of people
认为符号具有超自然力量
who ascribe extranatural powers to symbols.
哈佛大学
十字架
The sign of the cross.
如今
数字13
The number 13.
四叶草
Four-leaf clover.
幸运符号
Luck symbols.
厄运符号
Bad luck symbols.
能够治愈  诅咒  或是守护的符号
Symbols that cure or curse or protect.
这都是迷信
It's all superstition,
但是大家有信仰自由的权利
but people can believe what they want.
对吧
Right?
这是个自由的国度
It's a free country.
但是  什么情况下
At what point, though...
他们的信仰和你们对幸福的追求
do their convictions and your pursuit of happiness
会变得互不相容
become mutually exclusive?
温和的符号
When do benign symbols
何时会变得充满恶意
become malignant?
符号的解析
联合或灭亡
不要践踏我
兰木达  第十一个希腊字母
如果它们曾经有重大意义
What was relevant then
那么如今也依然有
is relevant now.
区别在于  如今人们轻点发送键
The difference is that now people can push symbols out to millions
就能将符号发给数百万人
with the click of a button.
将神话变为事实
Promoting myths as fact.
在这个后真相世界中  我们将何去何从
And in this post-truth world, where does that leave us?
我们该如何界定
Where do we draw the line
何时该尊重他人的信仰
between respecting the beliefs of others
及何时对它们嗤之以鼻...
and calling bullsh...
彼得·所罗门
-兰登教授吗  -你好
- Professor Langdon? Hello? - Hi.
我本来在等彼得的电话
I-I was expecting Peter.
我知道  抱歉  我是他的新助理
Yes, sorry, I'm his new assistant.
他让我给你打电话  告诉你
He asked me to jump on and let you know
一个紧急情况
about a kind of urgent situation.
他需要你的帮助
He could use your help.
怎么  史密森尼的秘书长自己不会打电话求助吗
What, the secretary of the Smithsonian can't ask his own favors?
确实有点突然  我知道
It's last-minute, I-I know,
但他说您能指望得上
but he said he can count on you.
我开玩笑的  你尽管开口
Oh, I'm-I'm kidding. Wh-Whatever I can do.
太好了
Terrific.
您能在5点前赶到华盛顿吗
Do you think you can get to D.C. by 5:00?
什么  今晚吗
What, like, tonight?
怛侄他  唵
Tayatha om
经文为《药师咒》
相传能消除病痛
鞞杀逝  鞞杀逝
bekandze bekandze maha
史密森尼实验室
贝塞斯达  马里兰州
鞞杀逝  鞞杀逝
bekandze maha bekandze.
三没揭帝  莎诃
Radza samudgate soha.
怛侄他  唵  鞞杀逝  鞞杀逝
Tayatha om bekandze bekandze...
红外热成像
齐拉法师情况如何
How's Monk-chella?
你自己看
See for yourself.
细胞排水量
温度
清水
这是实时画面  对吧
This is a live image, right?
细胞几乎完全停止生长了
So, cell growth has been almost completely arrested.
别忘了  这可不是普通的癌症
And keep in mind, this isn't just any cancer.
细胞排水量
温度
清水
废水
这些细胞分化性差
These cells are poorly differentiated,
抗化疗  攻击性极强
chemo-resistant, highly aggressive.
这些人念经就让细胞休眠了
And these guys sung them right to sleep.
这是一个重大突破
This is breakthrough stuff.
利用集中注意的力量
Harnessing the power of focused thought
比化疗的效果更好  是吧
beats the hell out of chemo, right?
而且我们也许只发现了冰山一角
And we may only be scratching the surface.
兰登  真意外啊
Langdon, this is a surprise.
什么风把你吹来了
To what do I owe this pleasure?
你该感谢你爸
Well, you can thank your dad.
显然  他晚会的主讲人生病了
Apparently the keynote speaker for his gala got sick,
他想让我代替出席
so he wants me to step in.
我不知道晚会的事
I don't know anything about a gala.
在国会大厦举办的史密森尼晚会
The Smithsonian Gala at the Capitol.
他没跟你说吗
He didn't mention it?
他可能说过  我最近太忙了
He may have. I've just been so buried.
但你能这么快赶来真是太好了
But that's nice of you to come in on such short notice.
你知道的  我愿意为彼得做任何事
You know I'd do anything for Peter.
是啊  还是个非自愿的观众
Yeah, and a captive audience.
-你这是诽谤  -得了吧
- That's a slander. - Come on.
用你的历史知识忽悠一屋子的有钱人
Beguiling a room full of wealthy, half-drunk patrons
还有喝得半醉的赞助商
with your historical expertise?
不就是你的梦想吗
It's pretty much your dream.
还不错  好了
That's nice. Okay.
我想我们也许可以一起吃晚饭
Uh, I thought maybe we could have dinner tonight.
我去不了
I can't.
-没关系  -我正在做实验
- Hey, no. No worries. - I'm right in the middle of an experiment.
我们发现了一些不可思议的现象
We're seeing some incredible phenomena.
比如  用意念移动骰子吗
Like moving dice with your mind?
我爸觉得他能做到
You know, my dad thought he could do that.
又来了
And there it is.
你知道我认为你很优秀
You know I think you're brilliant.
只是你研究的领域有点怪
It's just your field.
意念科学
Noetic science.
你应该记住这个词
You should remember those words.
总有一天  这个词会改写物理学
One day, they're going to rewrite physics.
-你什么时候到  -我没说吗
- When do you get in? - Oh, I didn't mention it?
我已经到了
I'm already here.
你们是在这认识的吗
Did y'all just meet here?
你找到约会对象了吗  在这里吗
You picked up a date? Here?
太...他真厉害  老兄
That-that... He's smooth, man.
我喜欢你的风格  老兄
I like your style, man.
我们要在这寻找真爱
We're finding love over here.
没关系  往前走  过来
That's okay. Come on. Step over.
我就知道会这样
I thought that might happen.
我戴了戒指  被绷带缠住了
I'm wearing a ring under this.
我手指肿了  戒指拿不下来
My finger was too swollen to get it off.
是吗  抬下手  谢谢
Oh, yeah? Open up. Thank you.
我女友说  男人不该戴首饰
My girlfriend says, you know, a man shouldn't wear jewelry,
但我不认同
but I disagree.
一定很痛吧
Must have hurt.
是啊  按说都30年了
Yeah, you'd think after 30 years,
我应该能在结冰的车道上
I'd be able to walk down an icy driveway
走路时不摔跤
without falling on my ass.
不  我是说文身
No, I-I meant the ink.
我背上纹了一个小美人鱼
You know, I got a Little Mermaid tattoo on my back,
纹的时候我差点哭了出来
and I almost cried when they put it on.
-小美人鱼  -是啊
- A Little Mermaid. - Yeah.
肯定是狂欢后遗症
Well, that must have been some party.
你懂的  荒废的青春
Well, you know how it is. Misspent youth.
大家都一样
Yeah, well, same here, I guess.
我想在没关门之前好好逛逛
I'd like to, um, get a good look inside before you close.
当然  没问题  你进去吧
Yeah, sure. Yeah, you're all good to go.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
你没事吧  先生
Everything okay, sir?
没事
Yeah.
我看不懂自己写的什么了
Can't read my own writing.
-谢谢配合  -谢谢  雕像大厅是这吗
- Thank you. - Thanks. Statuary Hall?
-上楼  左拐  -谢谢
- It's, uh, upstairs, to the left. - Thanks.
美国国会山
雕像大厅
游客勿入
不好意思  你好
Excuse me. Hey.
抱歉
Sorry.
今晚这里应该有一场史密森尼学会晚会
There's supposed to be a Smithsonian event in there.
日程上没有
Nothing on the schedule.
或许换房间了
Maybe it got moved to another room.
我是今晚的发言人
I-I'm supposed to give a speech.
不太可能  不过
I doubt it. But
别让这事阻止你  我很善于聆听
don't let that stop you. I'm a real good listener.
彼得
Peter.
这里没人  我记错时间了吗
Nobody's here. Did I get the time wrong?
没有  你完全按照指示行动
No. You followed directions perfectly,
这是个好兆头
which bodes well.
可大厅大门紧锁  根本没有晚会
But the hall's locked. Th-There's no event.
抱歉  可以让彼得接电话吗
I'm sorry, c-could you just put Peter on?
彼得在阿拉弗
Peter is in the A'raf.
穆斯林的炼狱
你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
天堂和地狱之间的分界线
The borderland between heaven and hell.
谢了  我知道阿拉弗是什么
Yeah, thank you. I know what the A'raf is.
他是否能返回到你的世界
And whether he returns to your world
亦或直奔下一程  取决于你此刻的行动
or moves on to the next will depend on your actions.
这座城市内  有一处古老的入口
There exists within the city an ancient portal.
我要你找到这个入口
Now, I need you to find it.
并开启它
And unlock it.
一个古老的入口
An ancient portal.
我知道彼得喜欢博人关注  可...
I know Peter likes to be the center of attention, but...
这样也太胡闹了
this is objectively extreme.
彼得  如果你在听的话  说真的  你该吃药了
Peter, if you're listening, honestly, consider medication.
对于一位知识渊博的人来说
For someone with so much knowledge,
你显得太无知了
you know so little.
不过这即将改变
But that will change.
你将破解这个世纪谜题
You will solve the great mystery.
看起来好逼真
It looks so real.
-而彼得将会给你指路  -他在哪
- And Peter will point the way. - Well, where is he?
如其在上
As above,
如其在下
so below.
喂
Hello?
好了  我们要疏散这片区域
Hey, okay, we're clearing this area.
-收起手机  先生  -女士  女士
- Phones away. Sir. - Ma'am. Ma'am.
先生  请收起手机
Sir, please. Phones away.
不要停  女士  谢谢配合
Keep it moving. Ma'am. Thank you.
清空这片区域
Clearing this out.
让这些人...让他们离开这里
Get these guys... Get these guys away from here.
请不要停
Please, keep moving.
谢谢配合  我们要关门了
Thank you. We're closed up now.
我们要清空这里  谢谢配合
Clearing this out. Thank you.
先生
Sir?
Sir.
我认得这些符号
I know these symbols.
他抓走了彼得
He's got Peter.
那是他的戒指
That's his ring.
待着别动
Stay right there.
失落的秘符
第一季第一集
为生蚝去壳
The shucking of the oyster.
我们从连接处切入
We break in at the hinge here.
然后我们...
Then we...
穿透内收肌
tear through the adductor muscle.
一定不要把外套膜弄破  好了
Sure not to break the mantle. Et Voilà.
别担心  他每年都这么做
Don't worry. He does this every year.
开生蚝还是TED公开课
The oysters or the TED Talk?
感恩节时我们被告知的谎言之一
One of the many lies told to us at Thanksgiving
就是美洲的早期移民吃火鸡
is that early American settlers feasted on turkey.
其实呢  鸭子还有可能  甚至是天鹅
Now, duck, maybe. Swan, even.
但绝对地  大量地
But most certainly, bountifully,
-是食用生蚝  -我爸爸宁愿我们
- on oysters. - My dad would rather us be
尊重史实而非开心
historically accurate than happy.
罗伯特欣赏历史
Robert appreciates history.
他也许是我认识的最聪慧的学生之一
He may be one of the sharpest students I've ever known.
但我告诉过他  原始智力只能让你到达一定程度
But I've told him that raw intellect can only get you so far.
而另外一方面  生蚝呢
Raw oysters, on the other hand,
就完全不同了
is a very different story.
实际上的确是
Indeed, it is.
-我没注意时间  -笛卡尔的确会让你这样
- I lost track of time. - Well, Descartes will do that to you.
我女儿正在写一篇关于《论灵魂的激情》的论文
My daughter is doing a thesis on Passions of the Soul.
一开始我还以为是一本浪漫小说呢
I originally thought it was a romance novel,
但我错了  并不是
but I was wrong. It is not.
但它的确把胡言乱语浪漫化了
Well, it does romanticize nonsense.
你读过他的著作吗
Have you ever read him?
我尝试过
I-I tried.
天才数学家  当他讲到
Genius mathematician. He lost me
松果体是通往灵魂的门户时我就放弃了
when he said the pineal gland was the gateway to the soul.
你能反驳这种说法吗
Can you disprove it?
我需要吗  以我来看
Do I need to? A-As far as I can tell,
他对解剖学的理解还非常原始
he had a prehistoric understanding of anatomy.
可他假定出了精神生理的定律
And yet he posited psychophysiological laws
-直到今天仍有意义  -精神生理
- that are still relevant today. - Psychophysiological.
对了
Oh, that's right.
彼得提到过你对伪科学很感兴趣
Peter mentioned you're into the pseudosciences.
他说过
Did he?
"非凡的头脑会被非凡的事情所吸引"
"A credible mind drawn to incredible things"
我是这么说的
is the way I put it.
我提议我们换个话题
I suggest we change the subject.
扎克里  不如你和我们说说你的行程吧
Zachary, why don't you tell us about your itinerary.
没错  我儿子要去中东
Yes, my son is going to the Middle East
围攻亚喀巴那里的沙滩
to lay siege to the beaches of Aqaba.
其实只是想要离开这里
Just to get away from here, really.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
我只是说
Oh, I-I just mean,
总是这个样子吗
is it always like this?
互相辩论  交流想法
Like, debating, exchanging ideas,
哪怕那些想法不算...特别理性
even if they aren't... credibly rational?
我的意思是...
What... I-I just mean, um...
你们非常幸运...
You're all very lucky...
能有这个家
to have this.
这次你真是中了头彩了  爸爸
You really hit the jackpot with this one, Dad.
每一年  所罗门教授接纳一个游子
Each year, professor Solomon takes in a stray
来过感恩节  作为某种慈善活动
for Thanksgiving as some sort of a charitable exercise,
可实际上  他就是要找
but, really, he's just looking
一位新的听众来奉承他
for a new audience to fawn over him.
他没有意识到的是
What he doesn't realize is
你和我们一样根本不在乎
you don't really care any more than we do.
我在乎
I care.
我认为他确实在乎
I think he really does.
我们能留下他吗
Can we keep him?
我认为他赢得了邀请  可以随时来
I think he's earned an open invitation.
等主管和你谈过后通知我
All right, let me know when you hear from the chief.
与此同时  我们搜查整座大楼
In the meantime, we sweep the building
-将其封锁  -收到
- and keep it locked down. - Roger that.
你是这里的负责人吗
Are you in charge here or what?
是的  暂时是
Yeah. Um, for now.
暂时  暂时是什么意思
For now? What does that-what does that mean?
等我一下  行吗  女士  你不能留在这里
Just give me a sec, okay? Ma'am, you can't be here.
-这是犯罪现场  -那么你也许不应该
- This is a crime scene. - Maybe you shouldn't let
让一群游客把这里的照片发到推特上去
a bunch of tourists tweet photos of it.
-什么  -只是我的想法
- Excuse me? - Just a thought.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我应该把这个拿出来
I should have this on.
佐藤井上  中情局特工
佐藤井上
Inoue Sato.
中情局  我以为联调局负责绑架案
CIA? I-I thought the Bureau handled kidnappings.
是的  有时候是  看情况吧
They do. Sometimes. It depends.
我不能再说什么了
I can't really say anything else.
顺便说一下  那两位是和我一起的
Those two are with me, by the way.
他们需要全部权限
They'll need full access.
我知道这只手可能属于彼得·所罗门
So, I understand this hand may have belonged to Peter Solomon.
对  你认识他吗
Yeah. You know him?
-听说过  -这是罗伯特·兰登
- Of him. - Ah, well, this is Robert Langdon.
他是所罗门先生的同事
He's a coworker of Mr. Solomon's.
-嫌疑犯给他打过电话  两次  -对
- The suspect called him. Twice. - Yeah,
但我们不是同事
we-we're not coworkers.
我在哈佛大学教书  符号学
I teach at Harvard. Symbology.
彼得是我的导师
Peter was my mentor.
今天早上  我接到了他助理的电话
This morning, I got a call from his assistant.
至少  我当时以为是他的助理
Least, thought it was his assistant.
他说  彼得想让我过来
He said that Peter wanted me to come down,
在国会大厦的晚宴上演讲
speak at the Capitol at this gala.
大家都知道彼得不太会考虑别人的时间
Peter's not known for his consideration of other people's time,
所以当时我并没觉得很奇怪
so it didn't seem out of the ordinary to me
-要立马坐飞机...  -罗伯特  深呼吸
- to get on a plane... - Robert. Take a breath.
这个人说过他的目的吗
Did this person say what he wants?
你不会理解的
It won't make sense to you.
还是先告诉我吧
Tell me anyway.
他说他正在寻找一个古老的入口
He said he's looking for an ancient portal
就掩埋在这座城市里
buried within the city.
他想让我找到并打开它
He wants me to locate - and unlock it.
这对你来说有什么含义吗
And that means something to you?
我直到看到那个才明白
It didn't until I saw that.
在另外三根手指上
On the other three fingers,
我想你们会发现更多的文身
I expect you'll find more tattoos.
太阳  灯笼  和钥匙
A sun, a lantern and a key.
他仿造了一只神秘之手
He's replicated the Hand of the Mysteries.
这是一个贯穿历史的符号
It's an icon you see throughout history.
是炼金术师和秘术家的信仰
The alchemists, the cabalists.
这是一封邀请函  邀请你越过神秘的大门
It's an invitation to seek a body of ancient knowledge
去寻找神秘的知识体系
beyond a mystical gateway.
一个入口
A portal.
疑犯在之前将手吊在石膏里  装成自己的手
Yeah, the suspect walked through security earlier
正大光明地走过了安检
with his hand in a sling like it was his.
而且我觉得他还做了伪装
And he was wearing makeup, I think.
-涂了遮瑕膏  -你的眼力很好
- Concealer. - You got a good eye.
看看警官能不能调出一些疑犯的照片
See if the sergeant can pull some security stills of the suspect.
彼得手上的戒指
The ring on Peter's hand--
三十三级共济会会员戒  据我所知
33rd-degree Mason. From what I remember,
有了这个就能接触到一些古老的知识
that comes with some ancient knowledge of its own.
无论人们怎么想
Despite what some people think,
共济会本质上就是个社交俱乐部
the Masons are essentially a social club.
但是  这仍然有可能是他被盯上的原因
Still, it could explain why he was targeted.
如果这个家伙认为彼得了解入口的事
If this guy thought Peter knew about the portal thing...
那么  他会非常失望
Then he would've been sorely disappointed.
彼得知道  这家伙想要的东西不存在
Peter knows that what this guy is after doesn't exist.
彼得有个女儿  对吗  你和她是什么关系
He has a daughter, right? What's your relationship with her?
-我们是朋友  -我们得确保她的安全
- Uh, we're friends. - We need to make sure she's secure,
我们也需要做个基因检测
and we'll need a DNA reference
来确认那确实是她父亲的手
to confirm that's actually her father's hand.
我来吧  我先给她打个电话
Uh, let me do it. Let me-let me call her first.
凯瑟琳  有情况
Katherine. Something's happened.
你父亲  他
It's your dad. He...
他被带走了
He's been taken.
我不知道到底怎么回事
And, um, I don't know exactly what's going on,
但是我们会把他救回来
but we're gonna get him back.
他们离开圆形大厅了吗
Have they left the Rotunda?
你不能待在这里  公园关门了
Hey, you can't be in here, man. Park's closed.
抱歉  我没注意
Sorry, I didn't realize.
我要挂了  妈
Hey, Ma, I got to go.
里奇
Rich!
这是你的吗
Those yours?
我看起来会穿那种衣服吗
Uh, does it look like I'd wear that?
所以之前在国会大厦的人不是你吗
So that wasn't you by the Capitol earlier?
没错  他们在审核我的最高法院职位
Oh, yeah. They were vetting me for the Supreme Court.
真可爱  身份证拿出来
Yeah, very cute. Let's see some ID.
我不想惹麻烦
Man, I don't... I don't want any trouble.
检查一下身份证  先生
Just want to see some ID, sir.
没问题  好
Of course. Yeah. Yeah.
别  住手
No! Stop!
不要
No.
解放  自由
Liberty. Freedom.
合众为一
E pluribus unum.
十三  十三  十三个州
13. 13. 13 states.
当地警方在运河路附近
Local PD found Solomon's car
一个停车场发现了所罗门的车
in a lot off of Canal Road.
没有监控  没有目击者  没有打斗痕迹
No cameras. No witnesses. No signs of struggle.
我要是知道我们对此案
You know, it would be helpful if I knew
真正的兴趣在哪就更好了
what our actual interest in this is.
我知道
I know.
解放  自由
Liberty. Freedom.
十三位少女
13 maidens.
他在干嘛
What's he doing?
不知道
No idea.
"彼得将会给你指路"
"Peter will point the way."
他在电话里说
He said that on the call.
我们上方的壁画是
The fresco above us
布鲁米迪所画的《华盛顿的神化》
is Brumidi's Apotheosis of Washington.
源于希腊语  "成为上帝"
From the Greek "Apo," To become, and "Theos," God.
那里  正中间
There, in the central panel,
乔治·华盛顿乘着云朵从凡人中飞升
George Washington is ascending on a cloud above the mortals.
他的蜕变时刻
His moment of transformation.
我想这个家伙也在告诉我们他想要什么
I think this guy is telling us what he wants.
神化
Apotheosis.
他以为接触了这些古老知识
To become a god. And he thinks he can do that
就能让他成为上帝
by accessing this ancient knowledge?
据说其中存放着能够
It was said to hold the keys to unlocking abilities
解锁人脑中潜藏能力的钥匙
that lay dormant in the human mind.
我只是跟着他的思路走
I'm-I'm playing catch-up,
可赎金竟然是超能力
but th-the ransom is superpowers?
他正在做的一切
Everything he's doing is-is in accordance
都与古老的条约一致
with ancient protocols.
神秘之手
The Hand of the Mysteries.
只存在于神圣之地
It must be presented in a sacred place.
-所以他选了这个房间  -神圣吗
- That's why he chose this room. - Sacred?
他们在礼物商店卖"我们人民"烈酒杯
They sell "We the People" shot glasses in the gift shop.
这是象征性的
It's symbolic.
这个房间是为了纪念
This room was built as a tribute
火灶神维斯塔神庙而建造
to the Temple of Vesta in Rome.
他的所作所为都有目的
There's a purpose to-to everything he's done.
还有他所说的一切
And everything he's said.
他说了什么
What is it?
"如其在上  如其在下"
"As above, so below."
这是他挂电话前的最后一句话
It's the last thing he said before he hung up.
我想...
I wonder...
等等
Wait.
在这  是罗马数字吗
There it is. Roman numerals?
不  根据减法计数法  这不是罗马数字
No. As a subtractive notation, it doesn't work.
-打扰一下  -可能是阿拉伯...
- Uh, e-excuse me. - It could be, uh, an Arabic...
-不是阿拉伯语  -不是吗
- Not Arabic. - No?
我擅长阿拉伯语
It's a specialty of mine.
我能不能插一句话...
If I can just interject for a quick second...
看上去像是如尼文的变种
Well, it actually looks like a runic variation.
小天才们  拿反了
Hey, smart people. It's upside down.
所以不是885  是SBB
So it's not 885. It's S-B-B. Right?
我们在国会大厦里面用这种计数系统
We use that numbering system here in the Capitol.
地下二层  第13号房间
Subbasement. Room 13.
好吧  出发吧
Okay. Let's go.
拜托
Come on.
抱歉了爸
Sorry, Dad.
你们来我父亲家干什么
What are you doing in my father's house?
米克尔·阿达姆  中情局特工
中情局
CIA?
该你了
Your turn.
让我看看你的证件
Let me see some ID.
那个怎么样
How's that?
我需要你跟我们去国会大厦
I'm gonna need you to come with me to the Capitol.
没有  拉里
No, Larry.
没想到  万能钥匙上没有万能这俩字
Surprisingly, the master key doesn't say "master" on it.
没有标签  只有数字  赶紧找
No labels. Just numbers. Find it.
好了  要下去了
Okay. Down we go.
你还好吗  来吧
You good, man? Come on.
我们在海平面以下  所以下面很潮湿
We're below sea level, so it can get pretty wet down here.
估计这也是没人愿意下来的原因
Probably why no one ever comes down anymore.
也没阻止彼得·所罗门下来
Didn't stop Peter Solomon.
他们刚刚告诉我第13号房间是他的私人空间
They just told me room 13 was designated as his private space.
这个钥匙孔比较奇怪
Oh, this keyhole's a bit funky.
这些钥匙都不行
None of these are gonna work.
等等
Hang on.
这个壁烛台
This sconce.
金合欢的枝条
Sprigs of acacia.
共济会把它当做永生的象征
Masons consider it a symbol of immortality.
你知道彼得会在这下面做什么吗
Do you have any idea what Peter would have been doing down here?
什么味道
What's that smell?
硫
Sulfur.
也许你没有自己想象的那么了解彼得
Maybe you don't know Peter as well as you thought.
这些像是人骨
These bones look human.
的确是
They are.
这本书  使用人肉装订的还是怎么
And this book, it's bound in human flesh or what?
只是本圣经
It's just a Bible.
这里不是什么祭坛
This isn't some sacrificial altar.
这里是共济会的反思室
It's a Masonic Chamber of Reflection.
被用来
Meant to be a place
反思自己的死亡
to come and reflect on one's own mortality.
用别人的大腿骨来反思吗
With some dude's femur?
这个比在四臂大象的前面吟唱
That any stranger than chanting before a four-armed elephant
或者比在被钉在十字架的人脚下祈祷还奇怪吗
or praying at the feet of a man nailed to a cross?
-怎么了  -这个符号
- Something wrong? - This symbol. The...
利维坦十字架
The Leviathan Cross.
不和谐  不应该摆在这
It's incongruous. It shouldn't be here.
那这个呢
What about this?
硫酸盐
"Vitriol."
这是缩写  你的拉丁文水平怎么样
It's an acronym. How's your Latin?
没阿拉伯语好  比德语强
Not as good as my Arabic, better than my German.
"入地心
"Visita interiora terrae
净化后必会找到秘石"
rectificando invenies occultum lapidem."
进入地心深处
Visit the interior of the Earth,
藉由矫正  你会发现黑色的石头
and, purifying it, you will find a dark stone.
其实是隐藏的石头
Hidden stone, technically.
你知道这是什么意思吗
Do you know what it means?
这是一个共济会咒语
It's a Masonic mantra.
"净化它  你将找到隐藏的石头"
"Purifying it, you will find the hidden stone."
你把钥匙放回灯台了吗
Did you happen to put that key back in the sconce?
你指这个吗
You-you mean this?
没有  没人告诉我放回去
No, no one told me to put it back.
我们也许该快点
Maybe we should hurry.
在炼金术中
In alchemy,
第一次净化是溶解
the first purification is dissolution,
表现为钙化物的溶解
represented by the dissolving of calcifications.
这些字是钙化物
These letters are calcifications.
这是盐
It's salt.
那堵墙
The wall.
我知道  这很令人惊叹
I know, it's remarkable.
不  是那堵墙
No, the wall!
我想它在移动
I-I think it's moving.
这些不仅仅是字符  它们是把手
These aren't just letters. They're handles.
-该死的  我拿不出来  -好的  我们没事
- Damn it, I can't get it. - Yeah, yeah, we're okay.
我们没事  请快点
We're okay. Hurry, please.
天啊
Oh, man.
那个  那个撑不住了  我们得走了
That's not... That's not gonna hold. We got to go.
当心  当心
Watch out. Watch out.
快点  快走  我们还在等什么
Hurry up. Come on! What we waiting for?!
快点  我们走
Come on, let's go.
快点
Come on!
兰登
Langdon!
一步一步来  快来
One step at a time. Come on!
你在开玩笑吗  快走
Are you kidding me right now?! Come on!
你已拿到这个了  快点  我们走
You've got this. Come on! Let's go!
向前迈一步  快点  继续向前
Take a step. Come on. Just keep going forward.
兰登  兰登
Langdon! Langdon!
兰登  快点  振作起来
Langdon, come on! Snap out of it!
快来
Come on!
我用了通用的共济会解密秘钥
I used a common Masonic decryption key,
所解出的明文  用专业术语说就是
and the, uh, resulting cleartext is, to use a technical term,
胡言乱语
gibberish.
也许你的解密方法不对
Well, maybe your decryption's off.
不是
No.
我认为这是个分段密码
I think it's a segmented cipher.
当希腊人想储存秘密信息时
When the Greeks wanted to store secret information,
他们会把信息刻在一块石板上
they inscribed it on a tablet,
然后把石板打成数块碎片
then shattered it into pieces,
每块碎片保存在不同的地方
storing each piece in a separate location.
只有集合所有碎片
Only when the pieces were gathered together
才能正确解密
could the secret be understood.
这可以解释为什么缺失了顶部
Which would explain why the top is missing.
尖顶石可以完善这段信息
The capstone could complete the message.
理论上如此
In theory.
你为什么来这里
Why are you here?
你之前说过
You said before that, uh,
也许我没想象中那样了解彼得
maybe I didn't know Peter as well as I thought.
他在为中情局工作吗
Was he working for the CIA?
不是
No.
是他
It's him.
稍等
Hang on.
-接吧  -像我们之前说过的那样
- Go. - Just like we talked about.
喂
Hello?
你找到了什么
What have you found?
我  我会告诉你
I'll... I'll tell you,
但首先  我想知道彼得没事
but first, I-I want to know that Peter's okay.
我需要证明他还活着
I want proof that he's alive.
他还活着  但是
Oh, he's alive. But,
无论怎么看  都在极度痛苦中
by any measure, in great distress.
你希望我相信你说的吗
You expect me to just accept that?
我希望你专注于你能控制的事情
I expect you to focus on what you can control,
比如  他是生还是死
which is whether he lives or dies.
我发现了一个小的花岗岩金字塔
There's a small granite pyramid.
包括数值网格
Contains a numerical grid.
但如果这是你的入口
But if this is your, portal,
那我恐怕我有一些坏消息
then I'm afraid I got some bad news.
这由我来判断
I'll be the judge of that.
破解网格需要进一步的背景信息
Any deciphering of the grid would require further context.
尖顶石
The capstone.
你不会以为这么容易吧
You didn't think it was gonna be that easy, did you?
我们还有很多工作要做  罗伯特
We have more work to do, Robert.
把它找出来
Find it.
我不知道从何开始
I-I-I wouldn't know where to start.
这就是旅程
Well, this is the journey.
而且已经开始了
And it's just begun.
找到了  离这4.8公里
Got the trace. Three miles away.
-快走  -我们马上赶去
- Let's go. - We're on our way.
你不能去
Not you.
我不会在这袖手旁观
I'm not gonna just sit here.
你是我们唯一的专家  我要你安然无恙
You're the only expert we have. I need you safe and secure.
听起来像是不允许我离开的委婉说辞
Sounds like a nice way of saying I'm not allowed to leave.
是不允许
You're not to.
他们没有燕麦奶  豆奶可以吗
Hey, man. They didn't have oat. Soy okay?
不行也得行了
Guess it'll have to be.
-谢了  -客气
- Thanks. - Yep.
听着
Look...
我知道你想离开这里
I know you want to get out there
帮忙找你的朋友
and help find your friend,
但是我想中情局女警胜任有余
but I think CIA lady's pretty capable.
我认为她有事瞒着我们
I think there's something she's not telling us.
这是个"知其所需"的世界
It's a "need to know" world, man.
我在沙漠驻过两次军
I did two tours in the desert.
我还等着有人告诉我原因
I'm still waiting for someone to tell me why.
他们喜欢秘密
They like their secrets.
是的
Yes, they do.
这么多关于入口的传言
All this talk about a portal,
彼得对我而言就是这样
that's what Peter was to me.
一个门户
A gateway.
通往书籍和艺术
To books. To-to art.
神话
Myth.
你认为自己无所不知
You think you know everything,
结果却遇到了真正无所不知的人
then you meet someone who actually does?
真是心灵受挫
It's, it's-it's humbling.
也许难以接受
And it could be hard.
他会鼓励我摒弃偏见
He'd push me to open my mind,
欣赏我的一些观点
appreciate points of view that I found...
即使毫无根据
...unsupportable.
晚上好
Good evening.
抱歉打断你们了  但是...
Sorry to interrupt, but...
我想我的打断反而让大家松了口气
I'm sure we're all relieved that I did.
不不不不不  我们在...
No. No, no, no, no. We were... We...
爸  你一个人在这里做什么
Dad, what are you doing in here by yourself?
整理我的讲座笔记
Working on the notes for my lecture.
你在回避你的客人
You're hiding from your guests.
回避你母亲的客人
Hiding from your mother's guests.
抱歉打扰你了  我们也许该...
Sorry to disturb you. We should probably...
我很高兴你们打扰我
I'm happy you did,
因为我想让你看看这些笔记
'cause I actually wanted to ask you about these notes,
你的看法总是会让事情变得更美好
and your thoughts always change things for the better.
好吧  这样吧
Okay, you know what?
我去拿杯酒
I'm gonna get us a drink.
爸  威士忌吗
Dad? Scotch?
不用了  凯蒂  谢谢
I'm good, Katie. Thank you.
感谢神灵  我有品位能介绍你们俩认识
I thank the gods I had the good taste to introduce you two.
凯瑟琳也许会说这是命运使然
Katherine would probably call it fate.
或是阿卡西场域中的永恒现实
Or the immutable reality of the Akashic Field.
你不相信这套说辞  是吗
You don't believe in that kind of thing, do you?
老天  当然不
God, no.
但你却相信凯瑟琳
But you do believe in Katherine?
如果你爱一个人  那最糟糕的事莫过于
The worst thing you can do if you love someone
让他们开始怀疑自己
is to give them reason to doubt themselves.
我们的伴侣  家庭  是我们的支柱
Our partners. Our family. These are people we lean on
因为他们是我们相信
because these are people we trust
并且也相信我们的人
and who trust in us
无论何种情况
no matter what.
我想我从未拥有过那种人
I guess I-I never had that.
现在你有了
You have it now.
是啊  他从未放弃过我
Yeah, he never gave up on me.
我也不能放弃他
I can't give up on him.
所罗门的手机
Solomon's phone.
世善被欺任其欺
-老天   -好了  那这雕像是个符号
- Goodness. - Okay. So, the statue's a symbol.
这家伙就喜欢这么干  对吗
That's how this guy works, right?
就像国会大厦里的壁画一样
Like with the fresco at the Capitol?
这跟雕像没关系
It's not about the statue.
而是关于铭文
It's about the inscription.
"世善被欺任其欺"
"Mundus vult decipi ergo decipiatur."
世界乐于受骗
"The world wants to be deceived,
便让其受骗
so let it be deceived."
受骗
Deceived.
好吧  听上去像是
Well, that sounds like
我们倾巢出动却一无所获
we brought everyone out here for nothing.
并没有倾巢
Almost everyone.
给西蒙斯打电话
Get Simmons on the phone.
是我
Yeah.
这里无事发生
Oh, it's all quiet over here.
是的  我们很安全
Yeah, we are secure.
好的
Okay.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
迈拉克需要你离开这里去找入口
Mal'akh needs you free of here to find the portal.
迈拉克
Mal'akh.
拿上那个  然后走
Take that and go.
他会联系你的
He'll be in touch.
他需要帮助
He needs help.
如果你再不走  他就只需要临终祷告了
He'll need last rites if you don't go.
警员受伤
Officer down.
-停车  -重复  接到警员受伤的报告
- Stop! - Repeat, we have reports of an officer down.
请求救护车  国会东路与第一街交界
Can we get EMS Code 3, East Capitol and First.
-这来自国会大厦内部  -待在车里
- That's coming from inside the Capitol. - Stay here.
-如果这跟我爸爸有关系呢  -待在这里
- What does this have to do with my dad? - Just stay here.
中情局
CIA.
还是没有兰登的踪迹
Still no sign of Langdon.
但已经派所有人去找了
But we've got everyone looking.
我想给你看点东西
I want to show you something.
全球即时命令
你问过我为什么对这案子这么在意
You asked about my interest in this case.
所罗门的孩子为我们工作过吗
Solomon's kid worked for us?
很短暂  在安卡拉
Briefly. In Ankara.
然后他因为贩卖人口被关了起来
Then he got locked up for trafficking.
三年前
Three years ago,
监狱发生了暴动
there was a riot in the prison.
扎克里·所罗门被殴打致死
Zachary Solomon was beaten to death.
所以  这之间有什么联系吗
So, what's the connection?
这就是你要去土耳其寻找的答案
That's what you're going to Turkey to find out.
兰登
Langdon?
Langdon!
兰登
小凯
Kat.
你在这里做什么  你还好吗
What are you doing here? Are you okay?
不  我并不好
No, not really.
你去哪  你...
Where are you going? What do...
天啊  你...
Oh, my God. Are you...
那是血吗
Is that blood?
不是我的
It's not mine.
告诉我发生了什么
Tell me what's going on.
你必须相信我
You're gonna have to trust me.
如果我要帮助你爸爸  我就得走了
If I'm gonna help your dad, I got-I got to go.
罗伯特
Robert.
抓走他的人想要我去找到一样东西
The people who took him want me to find something.
一件手工制品  一个古老拼图的一部分
A... A-An artifact, a piece of a very old puzzle.
-那我帮你  -不行
- Then I'll help you. - No.
他们刚在那边杀了两个人
They shot two people back there
就为了让我单独行动
so I could do this thing alone.
这不安全  我得走了
It's... It's not safe. I got to go.
我有样东西
I have something.
-凯瑟琳  -也许能有所帮助
- Katherine. - Maybe it can help.
是什么
What is it?
不知道  但我爸说它的秘密
I don't know, but Dad said that its secrecy
比他的性命还重要
was more valuable than his life.
他这么说的吗  原话就是这样
He said that? Those exact words?
差不多
Close enough.
他让我保证如果他有个三长两短的话就毁掉它
He made me promise to destroy it if anything ever happened to him.
我要跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
那是什么
What is it?
利维坦十字架
A Leviathan Cross.
情况有变
There's been a shift.
空气中出现了异样
A stirring in the atmosphere.
你能感觉到吗
Can you feel it?
你的命运现在掌握在罗伯特的手中
Your fate is in Robert's hands now.
人类的命运也一样
And the fate of mankind, as well.
但愿他不会令人失望
Now, hopefully, he's not a disappointment.
像你儿子一样
Like your son.
可怜  令人失望的扎克里
Poor, disappointing Zachary.
你根本不了解我儿子
You know nothing of my son.
可我了解
I do, though.
我陪他走完了最后一程
I was there with him in the end.
是我了结了他
I was the one who ended him.
兰登  我这是给你机会自己出来
Langdon, I'm giving you a chance to come out on your own
不然我就派人去抓你
or I'm sending someone else in after you.
罗伯特
Robert?
你挂了中情局的电话
Well, you just hung up on the CIA.
丹·布朗
《失落的秘符》
本季前瞻
我和彼得做了30年的朋友
I've been friends with Peter for 30 years.
是他带我进入了这个组织
He was the one who brought me into the group.
利维坦社的成立是基于一个信念
The Leviathan Group was formed based on
即古老的智慧解锁了隐藏的力量
a belief that the ancient wisdom unlocked hidden power.
如果这个力量落入坏人手中会发生什么
And what would happen if this power fell into the wrong hands?
你觉得彼得会为了保护那个秘密而牺牲吗
And you think Peter would die to keep that secret?
小心
Be careful.
要是还有其他选择我们也不会来这里
We wouldn't be here if had any other options.
关于佐藤你说对了  她有所隐瞒
You were right about Sato. There's something she's hiding.
做你最擅长的
Do what you do best.
救回彼得的唯一方式
Only way to get Peter back
就是找到尖顶石  满足迈拉克的要求
is to find the capstone, give Mal'akh what he wants.
时间不多了  我们必须完成这事
Time is running out. We have to finish this.
不然我爸就没命了
Or my dad is dead.
死亡对他来说是一种福气
Death will be a blessing for him.
你现在进入我的世界了
You're in my world now.